Eric Um

Katy, TX | LinkedIn | Website | Github | 615-580-9641 | eric@umericdev.com

PROFILE

Technology Professional with over 3 years in the Healthcare IT sector skilled in data analysis, troubleshooting and applications. Experience in building pipelines, utilizing Azure resources, and data management. Seeking opportunity to apply my knowledge towards as I continue my studies in data!

TECHNICAL SKILLS & PLATFORMS

Data Engineering | ETL/ELT, Data Integration, Data Processing, Dataloader

Programming | Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Database | PostgreSQL, Azure SQL Database, Azure Blob Storage, Data Warehouse, Relational databases **Cloud Platforms** | Salesforce, Microsoft Azure, Azure Synapse, Azure Data Factory (ADF)

WORK EXPERIENCE

DataTalksClub

Data Engineering Zoomcamp

February 2024 – Present

- Build data pipeline and dockized ingestion script to extract, store, and process large amounts of data in PostgreSQL database.
- Break down big sets of data (over 2 million rows) into smaller groups of 1000 rows for easier handling and storage.
- Develop scripts to automate data processing tasks using languages such as Python and SQL.

Acadia Healthcare

Salesforce Application Analyst

May 2021 - February 2024

- Built Salesforce flows to streamline user provisioning processes, reducing administrative workload by 20%.
- Led user automation project with DevOps and Development teams, providing field mapping direction and implementing logic for enhanced data accuracy, duplicate prevention, and system efficiency.
- Initiated the creation and execution of test scripts using Azure DevOps to thoroughly test new features, ensuring the absence of bugs and contributing to meeting sprint deadlines for the application's success.

Service Desk Analyst

September 2020 – May 2021

- Created an accelerated 17-page training guide with a comprehensive table of contents for new hires, enabling efficient onboarding and rapid familiarity with key technologies and challenges.
- Resolved 1000+ tickets, promptly diagnosing and solving hardware and software issues, ensuring efficient solutions and strong customer service.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Associate of Information Technology Major Cyber Security

August 2018 – December 2020

Motlow Community College

DP 900 - Azure Data Fundamentals (Microsoft)

DP 203 - Azure Data Engineer Associate (Microsoft)

NetSuite SuiteFoundation (Oracle)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Consistently achieved top ratings and most reviews in customer service desk evaluations.
- Reached the semifinals for code launch in Houston startups for a mock-up idea of ai app to estimate task time
- Contributed 40.14% of task completed of team of 6 and consistently resolved an average of 64 support tickets weekly, demonstrating operational leadership impact on Salesforce support.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Extract, Transform, Load Anxiety & Depression Symptoms Data [View Github]

Description: Employed ETL processes to analyze depression data, exploring race-related differences in anxiety and depression symptoms to identify trends.

Tools Used: CDC API, Visual Studio with Python, PostgreSQL, pgAdmin4, Flourish

Project Highlights:

- Extracted data on anxiety and depression symptoms through CDC API.
- Use Visual Studio with Python script for efficient data extraction, transformation, and loading.
- Implemented PostgreSQL as a reliable data storage solution.
- Utilized pgAdmin4 for seamless data querying and management.
- Created engaging visual graphs for data representation using Flourish.

Google API Integration for Houston Restaurants [View Github]

Description: Integrated Google API to retrieve data on Houston restaurants, utilizing Azure data tools to process and analyze API data.

Tools Used: Google Places API, Visual Studio, Azure Pipelines, Azure Synapse Studio, Flourish

Project Highlights:

- Obtained comprehensive data on Houston restaurants through Google Places API.
- Build data pipeline using python and extracted data and loaded into database storage.
- Utilized Azure Synapse Studio for creating SQL scripts to refine and analyze data.
- Created a visual chart for clear data representation using Flourish.

Web Portfolio with Data Engineering Projects [View Github]

Description: Developed a web portfolio showcasing various data engineering projects, emphasizing front-end skills and data-driven solutions.

Tools Used: Visual Studio, Azure Storage Account, Azure Static Website

Project Highlights:

- Created a front-end website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript using Visual Studio.
- Utilized Azure Storage Account for data management and hosting of the static website.
- Deployed and served static web content using Azure Static Website.